José Ferreira



contact@ferreiracode.com



linkedin.com/in/ferreiracode



+55 21 99938-6035



https://ferreiracode.com

Summary

A software developer with 6+ years of experience working on Web Applications. Motivated by creating the best experience for the client and the team. Passionate to see product ideas becoming reality through Design and Code.

Most focused on Front-end skills, but open to learning any tool need to fulfill the job in the best way possible.

Experience



Software Engineer

Blockade Games, INC

Dec 2021 - Oct 2022 (11 months)

- Implementing a redesign for a Web-based game using ReactJS
- Refactoring code from Javascript into Typescript
- Implementing Redux Toolkit to manage state into ReactJS applications
- Implementing a Design System using Storybook + Stitches CSS
- Implementing a platform to test out game rendering and mechanics through a WebGL pipeline
- Help to coordinate work between Design, Product, and Development team
- Writing, assigning and prioritizing work between different teams
- Give maintenance on Node.JS REST APIs
- Create new API endpoints to provide data to the client
- Create a new API to handle the testing environment for the game
- Provide support for the Frontend Developer to handle data changes on the API



Operations Manager

Foton Tech

Mar 2021 - Dec 2021 (10 months)

- Coordinate over 12 projects and 30 developers implementing software products on different Tech Stacks.
- Communication with clients to coordinate goals and priorities for the projects.
- Help developers to identify improvements points in their career
- Provide feedback for developers based on their deliveries and client's feedback
- Coordinate daily meetings to capture possible blockers and provide the correct support for the developers
- Apply Agile Methodologies to help teams to move faster
- Provide work as Software Developer on clients to help deliver faster and better software



Fullstack Developer

Freelance

Apr 2016 - Present (6 years 7 months +)

- Responsible to buil Software and Design Application

- Build REST API with NodeJS
- Build Frontend application with React
- Build Mobile Applications with React Native

Product Owner & React Native Developer

GetZION

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021 (3 months)

- Responsible for helping the team understanding tasks and drafting goals
- Responsible for aligning the whole team to deliver the best changes and features
- Responsible for communicating with users and clients to help improve the application

gj Frontend Developer

Great Jakes

Mar 2021 - Aug 2021 (6 months)

- Implementing and giving maintenance on Frontend applications for multiple Law Firms in the USA using ReactJS and NextJS
- Coordinate with different teams to deliver best User Experience for Law Firms sites



Fullstack Developer

Orc & Roll

Feb 2020 - May 2021 (1 year 4 months)

- Implementing different frontend pages for an online Tabletop Role Playing Game system
- Implementing reusable React components using Styled Components + Chakra UI
- Implementing complex, performative, and reliable Form systems to handle a Character System for a TRPG platform
- Help with coinciding ideas for design and improvements on the platform
- Implementing landing pages and marketing sites using React + Tailwind

Leste Fullstack Developer

Leste Telecom

May 2017 - Mar 2020 (2 years 11 months)

- Implementing a Warehouse Inventory System to help on managing all equipment and storage of an Internet Provider company with 50k+ active users
- Implementing a Call Center system to manage calls, clients waiting in queues, and support tickets system.
- Implementing a Client Central mobile application to enable 20k+ users to manage their Internet Service, pay bills, and ask for Internet installation.
- Responsible for designing and implementing a Service Orders Managing application for Technicians, that enables those employees to manage their daily work through a mobile application. That application was responsible for reducing paper usage in the company by 80%

Education



Colégio Aprovação

High School Diploma 2013 - 2015

Licenses & Certifications



React.JS, Node.JS & React Native Bootcamp | GoStack - Rocketseat

Issued Aug 2020 - Expires Aug 2021 36b15e7c-32b0-48ed-820b-91b3f8009317

Skills

Node.js • React.js • React Native • JavaScript • PostgreSQL • MongoDB • TypeScript • Next.js • Express.js • Tailwind CSS